structured query language sql or sql for short is the gold standard language for
结构化查询语言 sql 或简称 sql 是
communicating with relational database management systems you've likely heard
与关系数据库管理系统通信的黄金标准语言，您可能听说
of databases like mysql postgres microsoft sql server and oracle
过 mysqlpostgres microsoft sql server 和 oracle 等数据库，
all of which are based on sql with their own little variations
所有这些数据库都是基于 sql 的，
it was initially developed in the early 70s to mutate and retrieve data from
它们最初的变化很小 开发于70 年代初，用于
ibm's system r database by 1986 it was standardized into the syntax that
在 1986 年之前从 ibm 的 system r 数据库中变异和检索数据。它被标准化为今天
remains extremely popular in technical applications today a relational database
在技术应用程序中仍然非常流行的语法关系数据库将
organizes data into tables kind of like an excel spreadsheet where
数据组织成表格，类似于 excel 电子表格，其中
columns contain attributes or types of data
列包含属性或类型数据，
while each row represents an individual record or data point with its own unique
而每一行代表一个单独的记录或数据点，它具有自己的唯一
id known as a primary key we can establish
id称为主键，我们可以
relationships between data points by taking the unique id from one row and
通过从一行中获取唯一 id
storing it on a different row in a different table
并将其存储在不同表中的不同行中来建立数据点之间的关系。
in a special column known as a foreign key in the teams table the team id
团队表中称为外键的特殊列，团队ID
is the primary key but in the players table it's the foreign key
是主键b  ut 在球员表中，它是外键
and what that data structure tells us is that a player belongs to one team
，该数据结构告诉我们一个球员属于一个球队，
while a team can have many players what we've done here
而一个球队可以有很多球员我们在这里所做的
is structured our data in its smallest normal form to eliminate duplication and
是以最小的正常形式构建我们的数据以消除重复和
redundancy now the role of sql is not only to read
冗余现在 sql 的作用不仅是读取
create update and delete data but also to join
创建更新和删除数据，而且还根据嵌入其中的关系将
data together based on the relationships embedded
数据连接在一起
within it the syntax is comprised of several key parts if we
如果我们一直
zoom all the way out we have a statement or a piece of code
放大，我们有一个语句或一个语句，语法由几个关键部分组成 在语句
that does something like reads or writes to the database
中执行诸如读取或写入数据库
within a statement we have a variety of keywords that can manipulate the
之类的代码 我们有各种可以操纵数据库的关键字
database select can be used to make a query for
select 可用于从表中查询
the columns that you want from a table the column and table names
您想要的列 列和表名称
are known as identifiers but we may not want every
是 称为标识符，但我们可能不希望
row in the table so we filter the results with the where keyword to only
表中的每一行，因此我们使用 where 关键字过滤结果以仅
include records that meet a certain condition
包含满足特定条件的记录，
it's like looping over every row in the table and only returning rows in the
这就像循环遍历每个表中的行，并且只返回
query where the predicate evaluates to true
查询中谓词评估为true 的行，
then we might use the join keyword to connect data from an entirely different
然后我们可以使用 join 关键字通过将
table by matching the primary key on this
这个表上的主
table to the foreign key on another table
键与另一个表上的外键匹配来连接来自完全不同的表的数据
what we've created is a collection of clauses that make up
。 我们创建的是
a full sql statement we can now go and execute this code on the hundreds of
组成完整 sql 语句的子句集合，我们现在可以在数百个支持 sql 的不同数据库上执行此代码，
different databases that support sql this has been structured query
这是一种结构化查询
language in 100 seconds like and subscribe if you want to see a
语言，可在 100 秒内完成，如果您想查看完整的，请订阅
full sql tutorial thanks for watching and i will see you
sql教程感谢收看，
in the next one
下一篇再见